Tayler Nichols

Objective

Software engineer with a focus in web development. Seven+ years of experience designing and developing complex user interfaces, API's, and back end systems. Looking for a modern workforce that I can meaningfully contribute to, while being challenged with new ideas, technologies, and methodologies.

Strengths

- Full stack, innovative, self-directed software engineer with a proven history of developing interactive and responsive web applications, services, and APIs.
- Advanced education and continual research of web application practices and conventions, consistently integrating new technologies and tools.
- Known for writing clean and consistent code that is maintainable and testable.
- Thrives in a modern agile environment with regular exposure to emerging technologies and methodologies.
- ❖ Works well independently or in a team setting, drawing on excellent interpersonal skills to drive project objectives and ensure team success.

Experience

Senior Software Developer

R1 RCM | (Remote)

2021 - Present

- Agile based team with large releases to high priority medical applications.
- Development on a large Order Facilitator project.
 - .Net Framework 4.7.2 & TypeScript/Knockout.
 - Implemented complex fax interface.
- Sprint concurrent refactoring efforts.

Senior Software Developer (WebSelfStorage)

U-Haul | Phoenix, AZ

2017 - 2020

- Lead a CMS implementation initiative, offering affiliate customers to expose their own facility website.
 - .Net Core & Vue/React.
 - Cofoundry framework.
 - Azure Build & Release pipelines.

taynich.dev

tayler@taynich.dev 📧



602.540.4814



Phoenix, AZ 📌

Skills

Front End

HTML, (S)CSS, Bootstrap. JavaScript, React, Vue.js, Knockout. NPM, Webpack, Lint, Babel.

Back End

C#, .NET & Core, xUnit, NUnit. LINQ, EF, Sql Server. Swagger, SignalR.

Source Control

Git, TFVC.

DevOps

Azure(Build/Deploy pipelines).

Visual Studio 19, VS Code, SSMS. Postman, WCFStorm.

Process

Azure DevOps, Agile/Scrum, TTD, CI/CD.

Education

B.S. Network Security

University of Advancing Technology Tempe, AZ 2013

- Contributed to U-Haul's largest SaaS product, WebSelfStorage.
 - Agile/Scrum methodology.
 - Close interaction with product owners and stakeholders.
 - Advanced through several internal teams.
- Completed and enhanced Quickbooks & Sage 50 interface integration.
- Developed and deployed a suite(~12) of REST API's in tandem with an external kiosk team, used for integration in the physical facility kiosks.
- Enhanced and maintained existing internal SOAP services(~15) utilized by other U-Haul teams.

Senior Software Developer (Contact Center)

U-Haul | Phoenix, AZ

2014 - 2017

- Lead and completed rewrite initiative for internal Permission Management product.
 - Utilized by all internal products to manage user access.
 - o Rewritten in ASP.NET MVC using C# and Knockout.
- Lead development and implementation of a custom Cisco Calabrio product designed to assist
 & monitor customer calls.
- Developed internal support messaging system, U-Chat, using SignalR.
- Responsible for developing, maintaining, & enhancing a significant number of ASP.NET products(30+).
 - Co-lead scheduling and release process for all team products.
 - o VB, Web Forms.
 - o C#, MVC.
- Actively maintained Roadside Assistance, one of U-Haul's largest service products.
 - Contributed to rewrite initiative from Web Forms in VB to C# MVC.

Software Engineer/Tech Writer

SAIFE | Chandler, AZ

2012 - 2014

- Independently developed dynamic storage encryption solution.
 - Windows desktop solution.
 - User Interface developed using WPF in C#.
 - Storage management developed using Java.
- Contributed to completing an encrypted VPN solution for Windows using Java.
- Collaborated with a small team to develop an Android application designed for encrypted communication over text and voice.
- Wrote extensive product documentation, detailing technical details and functionality.
- Wrote many outlines and proposals for technical books.